<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on  </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on  </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.153.2</generator>
    <language>nl-be</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 08:10:36 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SMB Signing: A Critical Control Against NTLM Relaying and Lateral Movement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/smb-signing-a-critical-control-against-ntlm-relaying-and-lateral-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 08:10:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/smb-signing-a-critical-control-against-ntlm-relaying-and-lateral-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Server Message Block (SMB) is one of the most fundamental protocols in Windows environments. It provides file sharing, remote management and a range of operating system functions that depend on integrity and trust. When SMB signing is not enforced, NTLM authentication can be relayed to SMB endpoints, allowing unauthorised access to systems that accept unsigned connections. This behaviour forms the basis of several real-world attack paths and continues to appear in security assessments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LDAP Signing and LDAPS Channel Binding: Eliminating a Key Path to Domain Manipulation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ldap-signing-and-ldaps-channel-binding-eliminating-a-key-path-to-domain-manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ldap-signing-and-ldaps-channel-binding-eliminating-a-key-path-to-domain-manipulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Active Directory relies heavily on LDAP and LDAPS for authentication, directory queries and system management. These protocols underpin a significant portion of domain operations, including user lookups, group membership resolution, computer account provisioning and policy distribution. When LDAP signing and LDAPS channel binding are not enforced, NTLM authentication can be silently relayed to directory services, creating opportunities for unauthorised changes within the domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier discussions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://authumn.com/blog/dhcpv6-poisoning-an-overlooked-weakness-in-windows-networks&#34;&gt;DHCPv6 poisoning&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://authumn.com/blog/llmnr-nbt-ns-and-mdns-legacy-name-resolution-protocols-that-open-the-door-to-credential-exposure/&#34;&gt;legacy name resolution protocols (LLMNR, NBT-NS and mDNS)&lt;/a&gt; highlight how Windows hosts can be deceived into sending authentication traffic to a rogue endpoint. LDAP services become natural relay targets when these fallback mechanisms remain active. Without LDAP signing or proper LDAPS channel binding, directories may accept authentication that did not originate from the legitimate client, enabling a range of impactful actions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHCPv6 Poisoning: An Overlooked Weakness in Windows Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dhcpv6-poisoning-an-overlooked-weakness-in-windows-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/dhcpv6-poisoning-an-overlooked-weakness-in-windows-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Windows networks often operate primarily on IPv4, yet IPv6 remains enabled and active on nearly all Windows systems by default. Even in environments where IPv6 is not intentionally deployed, Windows continues to search for configuration sources that provide IPv6 parameters. This behaviour introduces an attack surface that is frequently underestimated: DHCPv6 poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technique has been known in the security community for years and continues to appear in modern assessments. Evidence collected for this blog uses mitm6 to demonstrate how easily Windows clients can be influenced when IPv6 behaviour is not monitored or controlled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMNR, NBT-NS and mDNS: Legacy Name Resolution Protocols That Open the Door to Credential Exposure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/llmnr-nbt-ns-and-mdns-legacy-name-resolution-protocols-that-open-the-door-to-credential-exposure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/llmnr-nbt-ns-and-mdns-legacy-name-resolution-protocols-that-open-the-door-to-credential-exposure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Windows environments rely on several name resolution mechanisms to locate resources when DNS queries fail or when systems operate in mixed or unmanaged networks. Among these mechanisms are LLMNR (Link-Local Multicast Name Resolution), NBT-NS (NetBIOS Name Service) and mDNS (Multicast DNS). Although created to support small or misconfigured networks, these protocols continue to operate silently in many modern enterprise environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their design introduces predictable weaknesses. All three protocols accept responses from any device on the local network segment. This behaviour creates conditions for credential interception when a system requests a name that cannot be resolved through DNS. For this reason, the protocols have long been associated with credential exposure and are frequently observed in security assessments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RDP - Big Brother is watching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/rdp-big-brother-is-watching-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/rdp-big-brother-is-watching-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remote Desktop has been a standard tool for system administrators and anyone who needs to manage a server or workstation from a distance for many years. During a session far more happens behind the scenes than most people realise. Windows quietly stores small fragments of the remote screen, a mechanism known as the RDP Bitmap Cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many users assume that once an RDP session is closed, anything that appeared on the screen disappears as well. In reality a portion of that visual data remains on the local machine. Forensic investigators consider this a valuable source of information, and in security-focused environments it is important to understand what this cache contains, how it works and which risks it introduces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
