<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on  </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on  </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.153.2</generator>
    <language>nl-be</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 19:33:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DHCPv6 Poisoning: An Overlooked Weakness in Windows Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/dhcpv6-poisoning-an-overlooked-weakness-in-windows-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 19:33:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/dhcpv6-poisoning-an-overlooked-weakness-in-windows-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Windows networks often operate primarily on IPv4, yet IPv6 remains enabled and active on nearly all Windows systems by default. Even in environments where IPv6 is not intentionally deployed, Windows continues to search for configuration sources that provide IPv6 parameters. This behaviour introduces an attack surface that is frequently underestimated: DHCPv6 poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technique has been known in the security community for years and continues to appear in modern assessments. Evidence collected for this blog uses mitm6 to demonstrate how easily Windows clients can be influenced when IPv6 behaviour is not monitored or controlled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RDP - Big Brother is watching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/rdp-big-brother-is-watching-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/rdp-big-brother-is-watching-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remote Desktop has been a standard tool for system administrators and anyone who needs to manage a server or workstation from a distance for many years. During a session far more happens behind the scenes than most people realise. Windows quietly stores small fragments of the remote screen, a mechanism known as the RDP Bitmap Cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many users assume that once an RDP session is closed, anything that appeared on the screen disappears as well. In reality a portion of that visual data remains on the local machine. Forensic investigators consider this a valuable source of information, and in security-focused environments it is important to understand what this cache contains, how it works and which risks it introduces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
